

# **Domenico Camasta**

☑ domenicocamasta@gmail.com 📞 3701522690 🔮 Via F. Baracca 8, Bologna (Italy) 🛗 29/12/1983

► Italian 👗 He/Him 🖈 portfolio.devcrumbs.com 🔘 d-cmst

# **Profile**

I'm a mathematician by education and self-taught software developer for passion, with over 10 years of experience building full-stack web applications with Python, JavaScript, Node.js and PHP. My expertise also includes system administration (Unix-based and Windows), databases management and data extraction/analysis.

Following a significant rebase in Bologna in 2022, I am currently in search of a job position that aligns more closely with my expertise and skills.

# **Professional Experience**

**Developer,** *UserTesting* □

2020 - 2022

• Developer | Python Data scraping expert

UK | Germany | Remote

**Developer,** Appen Ltd

2020 - 2022

• Developer | Python Chatbot Software

Remote

**Developer,** *UniD Formazione* □

2015 - 2019

• System Administration | Linux

Borgo Maggiore, RSM

• Developer | Python, Javascript, PHP Web apps

Teacher, MIUR □

2011 - 2014

Mathematics/Logic teacher for high school and university students.

Verona, Italy

#### Languages

**Italian** Native

**English** 

**TOEFL 2020** 

## **Education**

PhD, Università "La Sapienza"

2007 - 2010

PhD Program in Mathematical Logic | Thesis title: "A two-dimensional semantics for natural language formalization"

Rome, Italy

Master Degree, Università Degli Studi di Genova Italian Master Degree (Laurea Magistrale)

2002 - 2007

Genova, Italy

#### Certificates

TOEFL

Test date: 2020

Score: 98/120 (Advanced)

PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming

Year: 2019 Score: 92%

# **Projects**

**AGReATWine,** Contributor □

2020 – present

Creation of a database of Italian wines included in DOCG appellations, evaluated by the three main national wine guides

**KDE,** Contributor, Member □

2005 - present

Code, designs and translations for many desktop applications and web applications from the KDE ecosystem.

**ArchLinux,** *Package mantainer* □

2005 - present

Arch Linux is a Linux distribution that tries to Keep It Simple

WireGuard, Contributor ☑

2020 - 2022

WireGuard is an extremely simple yet fast and modern VPN

**GSConnect,** Contributor □

Complete implementation of KDE Connect especially for GNOME Shell.

**InvoicePlane,** *Contributor* □

A self-hosted open source application for managing your invoices, clients and payments.

RAMP, Contributor

Ramp is a python library for rapid prototyping of machine learning solutions. It's a light-weight pandas-based machine learning framework pluggable with existing python machine learning and statistics tools.

**Wiki.js,** *Patch contributor* □

Wiki.js is a modern and powerful wiki app built on Node.js

#### **Publications**

**Collana UnidTest,** Libri per la preparazione dei test di ammissione universitari

#### Other certificates

Italian Sommelier Association - Diploma 🗷

01/2020

Diploma di Sommelier rilasciato dall'Associazione Italiana Sommelier

Bologna, Italy